Guide to the Cosmopolitan Club records, 1904-1958.
Cosmopolitan Club records, 1904-1958.
Division of Rare and Manuscript Collections, Cornell University Library
Cosmopolitan Club records,
1904-1958.
37-4-441
Cosmopolitan Club (Cornell University)
4.6 cubic feet
Correspondence, newspaper clippings, programs, and records.
Division of Rare and Manuscript Collections, Cornell University Library
Scrapbook containing letters, newspaper clippings, and programs relating to the Cornell Cosmopolitan Club; scrapbook relating to International Student Association functions at Cornell; scrapbook relating to the founding and activities of International Student Association chapters at Berlin, Bonn, Göttingen, Heidelberg, Leipzig, Munich, and Zurich (1911-1913); photographs of foreign students at Cornell and of Cosmopolitan Club activities. Also, other correspondence and records.
COLLECTION DESCRIPTION
Correspondence, financial records, minute books, publications, memorabilia, scrapbooks and photographs relating to the Cornell University Cosmopolitan Club; correspondence includes records relating to the operation of the Club House, The International Federation of Students, Association of Cosmopolitan Clubs of America, The International Association of Ithaca, The International Student Service, Cornell University administration, correspondents include Edmund Ezra Day, Jacob Gould Shurman, John Mott and Donald C. Kerr; Financial records include financial activities and status of the Club and Association; Minute Books include official club business records of meetings and decisions; Membership records include a selection of the foudning members of the club; Publications including The Cosmopolitan Annual, Memorabilia consisting of commemorative programs and menus documenting official Club events, including Chinese Night 1906. Many of these items are autographed; Scrapbooks relating to International Student Association functions at Cornell (1932-1935); the founding and activities of International Student Association chapters at Berlin, Bonn, Gèottingen, Heidelberg, Leipzig, Munich and Zurich (1911-1913); scrapbook containg letters, newspaper clippings, photographs, christmas cards and other memorabilia documenting the Club founding, events and members; Photographs include individual and group portraits of Club members and administrative officers.
SUBJECTS
Names:
Cosmopolitan Club (Cornell University); Day, Edmund Ezra, 1883-1951.; Mott, John.; Schurman, Jacob Gould, 1854-1942.; Association of Cosmopolitan Clubs in the American Universities.; Cornell University--Students.; Cosmopolitan Club (Cornell University).; International Students Association.
Subjects:
Students, Foreign.
Form and Genre Terms:
Photographs,
RELATED MATERIALS
Consists of collections #37-4-145 and #37-4-441.
See also The Cosmopolitan Student, ARP 1227, and three cups and saucer from the Cosmopolitan Club Residence (MU-562-563, 1180, 1299, 1363) in #41-7-1964.
See also Addresses and Proceedings of the Eighth International Congress of Students, LB3602.I595 1913, http://www.archive.org/details/cu31924030605277
CONTAINER LIST
- Series I. General Correspondence
  - General Correspondence, 1913 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - General Correspondence, 1914-1925 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - General Correspondence, 1926-1929 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - General Correspondence, 1930 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - General Correspondence, 1930 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - General Correspondence, 1931-1932 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - General Correspondence, 1933 (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - General Correspondence, January-April 1933 (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - General Correspondence, January-April 1933 (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - General Correspondence, September-December 1933 (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - General Correspondence, 1934 (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - General Correspondence, January-February 1934 (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - General Correspondence, March 1934 (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - General Correspondence, April 1934 (Box 1, Folder 14)
  - General Correspondence, May 1934 (Box 1, Folder 15)
  - General Correspondence, June 1934 (Box 1, Folder 16)
  - General Correspondence, July-August 1934 (Box 1, Folder 17)
  - General Correspondence, September 1-14, 1934 (Box 1, Folder 18)
  - General Correspondence, September 15-30, 1934 (Box 1, Folder 19)
  - General Correspondence, October 1934 (Box 1, Folder 20)
  - General Correspondence, November 1934 (Box 1, Folder 21)
  - General Correspondence, December 1934 (Box 1, Folder 22)
  - General Correspondence, 1935 (Box 1, Folder 23)
  - General Correspondence, 1935 (Box 1, Folder 24)
  - General Correspondence, January 1935 (Box 1, Folder 25)
  - General Correspondence, February 1935 (Box 1, Folder 26)
  - General Correspondence, March 1-7, 1935 (Box 1, Folder 27)
  - General Correspondence, March 8-31, 1935 (Box 1, Folder 28)
  - General Correspondence, April-May 1935 (Box 1, Folder 29)
  - General Correspondence, June-August 1935 (Box 1, Folder 30)
  - General Correspondence, September 1935 (Box 1, Folder 31)
  - General Correspondence, October 1935 (Box 1, Folder 32)
  - General Correspondence, November-December 1935 (Box 1, Folder 33)
  - General Correspondence, 1936 (Box 1, Folder 34)
  - General Correspondence, January 1936 (Box 1, Folder 35)
  - General Correspondence, February 1936 (Box 1, Folder 36)
  - General Correspondence, March 1936 (Box 1, Folder 37)
  - General Correspondence, April 1936 (Box 1, Folder 38)
  - General Correspondence, May 1936 (Box 1, Folder 39)
  - General Correspondence, June-July 1936 (Box 1, Folder 40)
  - General Correspondence, August-September 1936 (Box 1, Folder 41)
  - General Correspondence, October-December 1936 (Box 1, Folder 42)
  - General Correspondence, January-February 1937 (Box 1, Folder 43)
  - General Correspondence, March-May 1937 (Box 1, Folder 44)
  - General Correspondence, June-August 1937 (Box 1, Folder 45)
  - General Correspondence, September-December 1937 (Box 1, Folder 46)
  - General Correspondence, January 1938 (Box 1, Folder 47)
  - General Correspondence, February-April 1938 (Box 1, Folder 48)
  - General Correspondence, May-September 1938 (Box 1, Folder 49)
  - General Correspondence, October-December 1938 (Box 1, Folder 50)
  - General Correspondence, January 1939 (Box 1, Folder 51)
  - General Correspondence, February-March 1939 (Box 1, Folder 52)
  - General Correspondence, April-May 1939 (Box 1, Folder 53)
  - General Correspondence, June-October 1939 (Box 1, Folder 54)
  - General Correspondence, November-December 1939 (Box 1, Folder 55)
  - General Correspondence, January-February 1940 (Box 1, Folder 56)
  - General Correspondence, March-April 1940 (Box 1, Folder 57)
  - General Correspondence, May 1940 (Box 1, Folder 58)
  - General Correspondence, June-August 1940 (Box 1, Folder 59)
  - General Correspondence, September-October 1940 (Box 1, Folder 60)
  - General Correspondence, November-December 1940 (Box 1, Folder 61)
  - General Correspondence, January 1941 (Box 1, Folder 62)
  - General Correspondence, February 1941 (Box 1, Folder 63)
  - General Correspondence, March-April 1941 (Box 1, Folder 64)
  - General Correspondence, May-June 1941 (Box 1, Folder 65)
  - General Correspondence, July-August 1941 (Box 1, Folder 66)
  - General Correspondence, September 1941 (Box 1, Folder 67)
  - General Correspondence, January-March 1942 (Box 1, Folder 68)
  - General Correspondence, April-June 1942 (Box 1, Folder 69)
  - General Correspondence, October 1942 (Box 1, Folder 70)
  - General Correspondence, November-December 1942 (Box 1, Folder 71)
  - General Correspondence, January 1943 (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - General Correspondence, February 1943 (Box 2, Folder 2)
  - General Correspondence, March-April 1943 (Box 2, Folder 3)
  - General Correspondence, May-June 1943 (Box 2, Folder 4)
  - General Correspondence, July-October 1943 (Box 2, Folder 5)
  - General Correspondence, November-December 1943 (Box 2, Folder 6)
  - General Correspondence, January-March 1944 (Box 2, Folder 7)
  - General Correspondence, April-May 1944 (Box 2, Folder 8)
  - General Correspondence, June-July 1944 (Box 2, Folder 9)
  - General Correspondence, August-December 1944 (Box 2, Folder 10)
  - General Correspondence, January 1945 (Box 2, Folder 11)
  - General Correspondence, February-June 1945 (Box 2, Folder 12)
  - General Correspondence, July-December 1945 (Box 2, Folder 13)
  - General Correspondence, January-February 1946 (Box 2, Folder 14)
  - General Correspondence, March-April 1946 (Box 2, Folder 15)
  - General Correspondence, May-December 1946 (Box 2, Folder 16)
  - General Correspondence, January-June 1947 (Box 2, Folder 17)
  - General Correspondence, July-December 1947 (Box 2, Folder 18)
  - General Correspondence, January-April 1948 (Box 2, Folder 19)
  - General Correspondence, May-December 1948 (Box 2, Folder 20)
  - General Correspondence, January-February 1949 (Box 2, Folder 21)
  - General Correspondence, March-May 1949 (Box 2, Folder 22)
  - General Correspondence, June-December 1949 (Box 2, Folder 23)
  - General Correspondence, January-June 1950 (Box 2, Folder 24)
  - General Correspondence, July-December 1950 (Box 2, Folder 25)
  - General Correspondence, January-May 1951 (Box 2, Folder 26)
  - General Correspondence, June-December 1951 (Box 2, Folder 27)
  - General Correspondence, January-June 1952 (Box 2, Folder 28)
  - General Correspondence, July-December 1952 (Box 2, Folder 29)
  - General Correspondence, 1953 (Box 2, Folder 30)
  - General Correspondence, January-June 1954 (Box 2, Folder 31)
  - General Correspondence, July-December 1954 (Box 2, Folder 32)
  - General Correspondence, 1955-1958 (Box 2, Folder 33)
- Series II. Financial Records
  - Financial Records Budget Ledger, 1906-1908 (Box 2, Folder 34)
  - Financial Records Budget Ledger, 1922-1926 (Box 2, Folder 35)
  - Financial Records Budget Ledger: Merchant and Member's Accounts, 1923 (Box 2, Folder 36)
  - Financial Records Club House Book, 1925-1926 (Box 2, Folder 36)
  - Financial Records Club House Book, 1928-1929 (Box 2, Folder 38)
  - Financial Records Budget Ledger, 1933-1936 (Box 2, Folder 39)
  - Financial Records Miscellaneous, 1938-1952 (Box 2, Folder 40)
  - Financial records Budget Ledger, 1939 (Box 2, Folder 41)
  - Financial Records International Association of Ithaca, 1953-1954 (Box 2, Folder 42)
- Series III. Administrative Records
  - Administrative Records Minute Book Board of Directors, 1904-1907 (Box 3, Folder 1)
  - Administrative Records Minute Book Club Business, 1907-1919 (Box 3, Folder 2)
  - Administrative Records Minute Book Board of Directors, 1909-1912 (Box 3, Folder 3)
  - Administrative Records Minute Book Board of Directors, 1912-1920 (Box 3, Folder 4)
  - Administrative Records Minute Book Board of Directors, 1913-1928 (Box 3, Folder 5)
  - Administrative Records Minute Book Board of Directors (Box 3, Folder 6)
  - Administrative Records Minute Book Club Business, 1921-1934 (Box 3, Folder 7)
  - Administrative Records Minute Book Board of Directors, 1921-1933 (Box 3, Folder 8)
  - Administrative Records Minute Book Board of Directors, 1928-1940 (Box 3, Folder 9)
  - Administrative Records Minute Book International Association of Ithaca, 1933-1958 (Box 3, Folder 10)
- Series IV. Guest Records
  - Guest Records Guest Book, 1907-1930 (Box 3, Folder 11)
  - Guest Records Guest Book, 1934-1937 (Box 3, Folder 12)
- Series V. Membership Records
  - Membership Records Life Records of Miscellaneous Members, 1896-1918 (Box 3, Folder 13)
  - Membership Records Index Cards, 1934-1944 (Box 3, Folder 14)
  - Membership Records Membership List, 1934 (Box 3, Folder 15)
  - Membership Records Miscellaneous Membership Certificates, n.d. (Box 3, Folder 16)
- Series VI. Publications
  - Publications "Argentina 1816-1902" (Box 4, Folder 1)
  - Publications Cosmopolitan Annual, 1907 (Box 4, Folder 2)
  - Publications Cosmopolitan Annual, 1907 (Box 4, Folder 3)
  - Publications Cosmopolitan Annual, 1907-1909 (Box 4, Folder 4)
  - Publications Cosmopolitan Annual, 1908 (Box 4, Folder 5)
  - Publications Cosmopolitan Annual, 1908 (Box 4, Folder 6)
  - Publications Cosmopolitan Annual, 1909 (Box 4, Folder 7)
  - Publications The Cosmopolitan Student, 1910 (Box 4, Folder 8)
  - Publications The Cosmopolitan Student, 1911 (Box 4, Folder 9)
  - Publications The Students of the World and International Conciliation, Eighth Annual Congress of Students, 1913 (Box 4, Folder 10)
  - Publications Published Material Miscellaneous, 1934-1954 (Box 4, Folder 11)
  - Publications The Cosmopolitan Review Convention Issue, 1936 (Box 4, Folder 12)
  - Publications Una Jornada by Modesto Quiroga, 1938 (Box 4, Folder 13)
  - Publications The Cosmopolitan Globe Annual Yearbook, 1952 (Box 4, Folder 14)
- Series VII. Memorabilia
  - Memorabilia Programs and Menus, 1905 (Box 4, Folder 15)
  - Memorabilia Programs and Menus, 1906 (Box 4, Folder 16)
  - Memorabilia Programs and Menus, 1907-1908 (Box 4, Folder 17)
  - Memorabilia Class Year Book, Pomfret School, 1908 (Box 4, Folder 18)
  - Memorabilia Programs and Menus, 1911-1919 (Box 4, Folder 19)
  - Memorabilia Alumni Record, Pomfret School, 1916 (Box 4, Folder 20)
  - Memorabilia Programs and Invitations, 1920-1926 (Box 4, Folder 21)
  - Memorabilia Programs and Menus, 1931-1939 (Box 4, Folder 22)
  - Memorabilia International Association of Ithaca Seal, 1933 (Box 4, Folder 23)
  - Memorabilia Programs and Menus, 1940 (Box 4, Folder 24)
  - Memorabilia Programs and Menus, 1941 (Box 4, Folder 25)
  - 2 copies of a poem by founder (Map-case Folder 1)
- Series VIII. Scrapbooks
  - Scrapbook International Student Association in Germany, 1911-1913 (Box 5, Folder 1)
  - Scrapbook International Student Association functions at Cornell, 1932-1935 (Box 5, Folder 2)
  - Scrapbook Cornell Cosmopolitan Club, 1904-1932 (Box 6)
  - Scrapbook Cornell Cosmopolitan Club loose pages, 1904-1932 (Box 8)
- Series IX. Photographs and other images
  - Photographs (Box 7)
  - 4 large photographs of the Cosmopolitan Club (Map-case Folder 1)
    Includes photo from 1913 of the house and participants of the Eighth International Congress of Students, held at Cornell by “Corda Fratres” the International Federation of Students, of which the Cosmopolitan Club was a member. A. D. White is pictured. The proceedings from this meeting were published and are available here: http://www.archive.org/details/cu31924030605277
  - Painting of Cornell Cosmopolitan Club (Map-case Folder 1)